<!DOCTYPE html>
<html lang="en">
<head>
  <meta charset="UTF-8" />
  <meta name="viewport" content="width=device-width, initial-scale=1.0" />
  <title>Sachi Weerasooriya — Research</title>
  <style>
    body { font-family: sans-serif; max-width: 700px; margin: 2em auto; line-height: 1.6; }
    h1, h2, h3 { margin-top: 1.5em; }
    a { color: #0366d6; text-decoration: none; }
    a:hover { text-decoration: underline; }
    img.portrait { width: 180px; border-radius: 50%; margin-bottom: 1em; }
    img.figure { width: 100%; max-width: 600px; margin-top: 0.5em; border: 1px solid #ccc; }
  </style>
</head>
<body>

  <h1>Sachi Weerasooriya</h1>
  <p>Postdoctoral Researcher • Galaxy Formation and Evolution</p>

  <!-- Portrait -->
  <img src="images/portrait.jpeg" alt="Portrait of Sachi Weerasooriya" class="portrait">

  <h2>About Me</h2>
  <p>
    I am a postdoctoral researcher modeling galaxies for future surveys, such as Roman, with a 
focus on accurate modeling of emission lines and calibrating models using the Semi-Analytic Model Galacticus. 
My other research interests are modeling dwarf satellites of the Milky Way and Centaurus A, and exploring the
impact of major mergers on stellar streams and their properties.
  </p>

  <h2>Research Projects</h2>

  <h3>Modeling Emission Lines</h3>
  <p>
    Using the <strong>GALACTICUS</strong> semi-analytic model,
    I have implemented an improved model for emission line luminosities
    in HII regions, incorporating the Cloudy models, building upon the model
    by Merson et al. 2018 for star-forming galaxies. I have implemented an
emission line model for the AGN in model galaxies, drawing inspiration from
the work of Feltre et al. 2016 \cite{Feltre+2016}. This model employs \texttt{CLOUDY}
Ferland+2013, Ferland+2017, to create detailed photoionization models of the narrow-line regions in AGN.
  </p>
  <img src="images/project1.jpg" alt="Predicted star-formation histories of Milky Way dwarf galaxies (solid curves) and observed SFHs in dashed curves." class="figure">

  <h3>Dwarf Galaxies of the Local Volume <span>(Weerasooriya et al. 2023,2024)</span></h3>
  <p>
    My Ph.D. thesis began exploration of the dependence of the SF physics of dwarf galaxies on the environment
by modeling dwarf galaxies of the MW and an intermediate mass-environment (Cen A) using \texttt{Galacticus}.
SAMs formulate galaxy physics onto a dark matter-only N-body simulation, are computationally inexpensive, and
allow us to explore this massive system's parameter space rapidly.
  </p>
  <img src="images/project2.jpg" alt="Luminosity metallicity relation of Milky Way dwarf galaxies" class="figure">

  <h2>Contact</h2>
  <p>
    Email: <a href="mailto:sweerasooriya@carnegiescience.edu">sweerasooriya@carnegiescience.edu</a><br />
    GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/sachiwee">github.com/sachiwee</a>
  </p>

</body>
</html>
